Thank you all for coming this is
about implementing transparency
in reproducibility in economics my name
is Lars ill humor I wear a lot of hats
I speak for none of them all of this is
my opinion except when it's expressed as
policy for
the American Economic Association I guess.
The background to where we're coming
from is the skull of this chorus
think of it as publications but
ultimately publications are only part
of a skull of a discourse that
is in person in exchanges
nowadays on Twitter back in
the 18th century by by letter.
The basic idea is that we exchange
ideas I'm going to be focusing
here on publications and
publications early on contained more or
less everything that was needed to support
the arguments that were being made
when it relates to data contained tables
of the data and the math in general
if you think about the early 20th
century it was relatively simple.
As data became electronic and
as math was transcribed to code
some of the elements of these publications
started to disappear from the publication
record because in part they were
difficult to access difficult to store
difficult to preserve if you think
of the sixties and seventies when
computer code was implemented on cards
in a definitely a transitory way
then it was very hard to sight it was
a very hard provided to somebody else.
This is my my favorite picture taken of
the very 1st issue of
the American Economic Review in 1011
the argument was about seasonal
variations in New York money market and
the data was provided as a big fold of
table publication format was adapted to
accommodate that this was larger than any
single page but it needed to be provided
to any reader of this in a way that
allowed them to look at what was going on.
What we see today is often
a poor proxy for this and
if you look at how this looks on Jay's
store you have to scroll through 3
Scan p.d.f. pages that don't exactly
replicate what's going on here so
to some extent this hasn't gotten
much better there are of course
nowadays way many different ways of
highlighting these attributes and
publication but the key part is that data
tables like this in whatever format they
are in that particular machine readable
formats have been one of the issues that
are the absence of their
presentation has that for
mental to the idea of reproducibility So
my my motivation here is that modern
publications need to reacquire
similar transparency in completeness
as in the old simpler days and
that's a lot of what
the discussion has been about and.
We need to define 1st why that is
important what that actually is so
when I say replicability what
we actually mean by it or
we actually mean what I call the
replication continuum and there's various
definitions out there that have started to
standardize some of the terms around this
because there have been many different
terms that have been given over time.
I will often use replicability it
just flows easier all the time within
reproducibility in particular
when you start conjugated.
But the definition in the this report and
others have sort of coalesced
around following me Priscilla t.
is and often mentioned as
computational reproducibility is when
you have the same data the same code the
same methods the same context think of it
as an audit study what you see in front of
you actually produces what's in the paper.
It has been called other terms
in the in particular in economic
literature whether it be narrow
replication purification verification and
cetera and
I will often use the term verification
of computational reproducibility to
to describe what we are doing at the.
Replicability as is when you
take a step back from that so
replicability means we're going to start
implementing something with different
codes different aspects of the code
different model different software
you might also do a new data
collection extend that they collect but
basically still on the same population
using fundamentally the same methods and
in this income things much of those
might occur within the same paper these
are the robustness tests that
your referees have asked for
that go into the appendix or that go into
further section on the robustness test so
they need not be something very
different in a different publication
generalizability on the other hand does
go beyond any single paper
it's when folks started to.
Apply this to a very different
background when different data is being
used different methods are being used
different contexts or countries are being.
So that's sort of the overall framework
and there has been progress towards
improving what I hear mentioned
earlier the clarity and
availability of a common discourse about.
The subjects of articles so for one and
we'll be talking a lot about this
replication archives and data Villa built
the policies have been around now for
quite some time the 1st of these started
to emerge in the middle of the 1980 s.
they expand it substantially in the early
2000 the oldest replication archive is
the Journal of Applied
econometrics goes back to 1905 but
most of these journals have at some point
coalesced around a relatively common
standard of data available to policies but
part of that this course is also
shared open source software where there
are those are state packages or are itself
are all features that appeared
in the early 2000 and
they facilitate the discussion about
what's going on because now you actually
have a share platform where you can see
these these analysis being conducted.
Over the past 20 years better public using
shared data has emerged where that's open
easily downloadable public
like I see kids are.
Or restricted access to research
they don't it works of this world
the federal one the Canadian one even
local ones in Quebec or in France or
in Germany are of are a product of the 2
thousands that have vastly expanded
joint common very open access
to data that underlies some
confidentiality restrictions but yet it
is accessible to hundreds of researchers.
And better ways of accessing pretty
Prince is also a reaction to the absence
of a larger discussion
the idea that you might share
publications prior to their appear of you
and prior to their publication the more
formal that you're with off call the great
literature is a product of the early 2000
were computers in economics go back to
the seventy's but both in economics and
in physics mathematics archive these
expanded greatly in the early 2000
so it doesn't mean that we have
no reproducibility issues well
the recent discussion about
replicability crisis clearly says no.
On this continuum of just checking for
reproducibility
the simply testing materials as provided
by authors the graph here shows
statistics just a heuristic I don't want
to go into many of the details about
various tests that have been done over the
years and they tend to gravitate around.
Low twenty's 30 percent with colored
dots at the end are from an experiment
that we ran a couple years ago of going
through all the replication archives of
one Journal of the American Economic
Association and there is a definitional
issue which reads to their bean multiple
thoughts there as to what is actually
perfect reproducibility if you classify
something as reproducible if it is
partially reproducible you use the access
to the data as a criterion for
selecting what you even attempt to do and
so these very along these lines.
The relatively high percentage that's
shown there is that when they die is
available and we succeed in reproducing
at least half of the tables and
figures in the paper we classified it as
reproducible and that is about 85 percent.
The breakdown here is that there is a
large fraction within economics that uses
restricted access data and so is 85
percent of when the data is available
half full or half empty glasses is
a matter of discussion many in the open
access community see that as a tremendous
all there is currently discussions under
e.p.a. to rules to consider whether
data that cannot be openly shared
is actually appropriately used for
analysis and or policy
failure to cure rate should have been
obsoleted by the data availability
policies by authors providing
the materials to the journals but
is still something that is of concern
especially when the cannot be shared
in a variety of ways percent
Asian practices make tracking
down which data was actually used when
it is not provided quite difficult time
so these are actual quotes from papers and
there is the full
extent of how the data was actually
sourced and that may not always be enough.
But archives or data providers are also
part of the problem because many
don't provide permanent locations and
there are a few high profile over and
stations participating in this call
as they are on every one of these
presentations that I've given and
the they are challenging at times for
researchers to identify where they got
the data from because the data provider
themselves do not necessarily provide very
clear dissin structures on where the data
might be 5 or 10 years from now so
what can we do
the 1st realization was in many of
the social sciences at least that you need
stronger enforcement of such data and
actually code availability policy.
So it's not sufficient to simply post
such a policy to get some sort of package
thrown on to your website and be done as
it turns out that doesn't work reliably
and so starting particular with the
American Journal of Political Science but
then expanding including to the n.e.a.
but also other econ journals greater and
Foresman of these policies has been
a recent innovation if you want
so verifying the reproducibility is one
key to improving the overall weepers built
to do so prior to publication introduces
additional complexity that I'll talk about
you know that but current they develop
military policies were also broken so
for one if the data act was not open
access so say it was a restricted access
data set the basic approach
was to grant an exemption but
exemption then meant that you also no
longer provided systematic information as
to where you got the data from and that's
very important but on the other hand
should you even provide the data for
such deposit if the data are already
somewhere else so you destroyed by
requesting that the data be deposited you
often destroyed some of the provenance
information that came with it and
if they don't are at what we would
consider to be very robust archive should
you even ask to have the positive
you should definitely a scribe
where they are and so some of the movement
in the last couple of years has been about
requiring greater transparency of the
provenance of data and code and figuring
out ways to get authors to provide that
information to displayed in journals.
You might have why were
journals actually asking for
these supplemental zip files and
all these things will show you want for
one that obsolescence of various web
pages leads to an availability of
these things over time journals
can ensure a legitimate and
persistence of these archives by
taking custody of these objects and
putting them on to their websites
you can ensure access our website so
we know that you can access that
something's not going to go away or
that won't be any complicated things
accessing with the Cabinet of course that
there might be pay walls and they can
ensure that the availability is there but
that's precisely what trusted repositories
have as a business purpose call the data
archives call them trusted repositories
their goal is to ensure such longevity
persistence access and build built and
with the advent of new
self deposit repositories this has become
easier over time now itself the positive
positive words are not a replacement for
properly curated data at professional
repositories there's a difference between
dropping something into a bucket and
being sure that it is going to stay
around for the next 203050 years and
actually creating data documentation and
other things that relate to that but
this is a huge advance there
are a number of sites out there data
Versteeg share open i.c.p. is ours in
OTOH most of them are free some of them
are with a commercial base some of them
are nonprofit so there's a huge diversity
that allows researchers at various
stages in their research lifecycle
to deposit data and ensure at least
the permanence and the accessibility of.
But what do we do about the restricted
access to the well in fact
many of the same networks have
grown into the equivalent
of a data repast atory of
it they don't archive.
There are a number of people from the fs
r.t.c. on this call and clearly that not
work has acquired attributes that
are more a big bully associated with at
with open archives elsewhere the data is
preserved the data is made available and
there is a process for accessing it
just isn't a simple ballot and so
they have many of the same features
of these of trusted positiveness So
the idea is to use trust
repositories wherever possible but
also going back to the previous light to
describe the provenance from the stress
preposterous of the analysis
results all the way into the paper
now there are problems with that for one I
mentioned earlier the curation problem and
cetacean problem when we
started to expand to other
allowable repositories not all are created
equal to start with the most obvious thing
that I get to see a lot of times get
up Dropbox and the same are not data or
code repositories at all at any point
in time somebody can delete their stuff
from Dropbox there's no permanence
that is insured in any way and
those are commercial companies
that might go out of business and
who knows what they have in terms of
a permanence or a transition policy but
it also applies to various institutions
whether you might be thinking of
an institutional University repository
in a zone in a conflict zone
whether you're talking about at Cornell
where I I think it might be reliable but
is it actually for the next 20 years or
a big institutions like our Are the
National Archives a reliable Republican
they rely on funding that is not
necessarily assured for 50 years.
Restricted access repositories or similar
if I can take custody of the data as they
don't have to stay someplace How long will
it stay there and what are they doing to
preserve it if I'm using data from
some bank will they preserve it so
that even if somebody else is allowed to
access it 3 years 10 years from now will
there still be data how about school
districts how about research institutes
affiliated with private institutions
about the sense of fear.
So while many of these may actually be
good repugnant Tories the challenge for
for people using them is to figure out
are they actually were positive so
there is a need to describe them
describe them in various ways
infrastructure to support that kind
of description is evolving and
one of the key things is to say now
that this is definitely not something
that originated in economics
the idea of fair meditate and
fair data is all about figuring out how to
preserve these data in an open a fashion
and it should be pointed out the fair data
principles apply primarily to manage it so
it's the meditator that has to be
open they don't need not be but
it needs to be find of all accessible
interoperable and reuse assessing that for
various repositories around
the world is a challenge.
They say cation principles help with that
but said they decide to Asians themselves
or not enough principles have
enough information in them to be
useful but they decide to actions as
we see them in journals actually do not
because they tell you where there might
be if they are sufficiently precise but
they don't really tell you who
can access for how long and
under what conditions principle These are
covered by this efficient principles but
they're not covered by the style
guides that we tend to use for
these kind of things if
even we do get a situation.
So emerging to support of better
transparency of that have been data
they'll ability statements I'll
get back to what that implies at
the American Economic Association you know
that so they develop built the state and
expand on data citations the do not
replace data citation they allow
authors to have clarify where the data is
including various ways of accessing that
they should highlight reasons how
the data can be made available or
not which increases transparency they
shouldn't principle say something
about how long the data would be
available and about usage rights.
We tend to think for instance that
government data is in the public domain
but that's not always true
elsewhere in the world and
that may not be obvious to other readers
who are not familiar with what the u.s.
government rules on these things are and
that is that extends to
all sorts of things just because you can
download it from the internet does not
actually mean that you have the rights
to give it to somebody else and so
the usage rights are very
important to convey So
all of that leads to the goal and the need
to improve the provenance documentation
of the data assets that go
into our publication so
why should we actually care about for
one and this is
statement of desirability not necessarily
the most convincing argument for
people who think that we are credible the
credibility is one of the key facets here
think of statements about the long
run impacts of an epidemic and
I'm not talking about the most recent
one I'm talking about the color
if you want to believe
statements about the effect
of that Demick on long term outcomes
you're going to see graphics
that sort of describe this analysis
that look at these kind of things
you want to know where these come from and
that ultimately means
that you need to look at where
the data underlying it comes from.
And those might be quite old but
you still need to find some of it and
you need to be sure that those
are the relevant ones that's what
academic discussions actually imply So
once you have that idea there you
can now think of where is the data
store that was used for this analysis and
you can go in and download that data.
Or.
You can download that data and
you can download the code for that.
And you can look at the code and you can
now assess as a scientist whether or
not this analysis makes sense you
can rerun it you can apply other
things you can replicate it and
you can possibly expand or generalize it.
And that's what better a positive is
associated with journals are doing so
the credibility of the claims in the paper
a lives on the transparency of every piece
of the aspect there all the way
back to the source data
the methods to transform that and
then finally you know.
That credibility is key to understanding
the statistics that we see around us or
this we see in the scientific literature.
Ok so
let me then switch to what we're doing
at the American Economic Association.
The American economic says Asia has
Eternals and the policies that are going
to describe apply this point to all
8 of them to varying degrees as
they came into the process
that we developed so
in a nutshell we have aspired to do 3
other things 1st to preemptively improve
code archives 2nd to
create better archives and
in particular to ensure that they have
greater transparency and coming Corporate
it into the scientific architecture and
overall better provenance truck.
Over time that means to leave code aware
of where it is when that is appropriate
and to leave data where it is when that
is appropriate that is a challenge and
I'll get to some of those aspects so
the policy has been around for
a while but what we did is we changed
some of the policy to reemphasize
some of these key aspects
to it clearly and
precisely documented wasn't always the
case before we start enforcing this and so
we will look at that readily available
our aspects both for data and for
code that can be tested and we test that
and it used to be that the emphasis was
to provide prior to publication that turns
out sometimes to be a challenge to get
authors once a papers accepted to provide
the materials on time the policy asked for
details sufficient to permit replication
that's an aspirational goal and
we set out to modify the policies that we
are actually going to start testing that
and we used to post things on
the a website I just showed an example of
a recent publication where we have
moved to a new infrastructure so
considering these things last year in
July we expanded on this policy and
clarified a few things 1st of all point is
that the access to the data in the code
is clearly and precisely document and
we emphasize the fact that it has to be
non-exclusive to the office non-exclusive
means there needs to be a reasonable way
in which others can access the same code
and the same data we moved to requiring
these materials prior to acceptance and
believe me that into his a very
high degree of compliance because unless
those materials are provided the paper
doesn't actually get accepted and
we actually test some of
the information about access to data.
As well as whether it's sufficient.
And we moved on to posting on the website
to being archived in a repository where we
collaborated with the openness p s r
to have a journal specific repository
you know itself that's not
an innovation others have done that
way before the American Economic
Association but it's important for
part of the creation of it archives so
let me describe a bit what we actually
do for these 3 different components
preemptively improving code archives means
we actually conduct reproducibility we run
code as provided by the authors we use the
data as provided by the authors we will
download data as instructed by the authors
and when I say by the authors it is
in writing in the read me that everybody
else can see after it's published so
no private correspondence between us and
the authors in general other than to
clarify whether you know we are your
guinea pig essentially as authors
because afterwards anybody else should be
able to do exactly what we did except we
do it prior to publication now 40 percent
of They'd are not accessible What can we
do there we work with groups that actually
can conduct reproducibility checks for
us when we cannot and
that doesn't need to be very complicated.
We have sometimes obtained data from
groups where the data is proprietary but
not necessarily confidential and so
we have been able to run reproducibility
checks there we have work with groups
who have access to say the universe
of tax files in the United States that
we didn't have access to ourselves and
we asked them to run reproducibility check
on their colleagues but not co-authors So
we have worked successfully with a lot
of groups the the complexity of data
access sometimes means that we
are going to ask others to run that for
us we have been quite successful with.
What we do is that for
every paper we verify
these various aspects 1st of all
provenance documentation we look for
data fixations I'll show you what those
might look like it is a key aspect it has
been in principle and the a is guidelines
for a decade but very poorly enforced so
we enforce that now we look at the quality
of the review can we actually understand
what's being said in the week is
that just a one line to run this
thing with no information about where
to get the data or what to do or
is it a very explicit read and we've seen
everything from the 2 liners to the 50
pages we look at the quality of the code
and I'm not saying that we are checking
that the code is right that is of
a very different of magnitude.
We are checking to see is it clear
from the code where table one is being
generated were analysis data
step one is being created and
why certain aspects are being.
It is is this intelligibly documented and
then if we have the data on the code and
enough instructions in reach me
we attempt to follow those instructions
to reproduce the analysis and.
Finally we look at the Met in the
repository that I'll show you in a moment.
I should emphasize we only
do a reproducibility check
we do not do replication or generalization
that's for the literature to do but
we ensure that that 1st step that at least
this run of the and these results and this
paper have some unbearable basis to them
and that the next persons can start from
that basis to then start modifying the
various other aspects on the replication.
All the guidance we provide the remains
that we expect to have which should been
read me the replication template
that we use are posted publicly so
anybody who thinks of
submitting an article and
Copely getting it accepted at the American
economic associations journals
can look at our various websites and
find the guidelines for it so
there's no no surprises who is
doing this well the checkers
are not seasoned economists with tenure
they're undergraduates not necessarily
all from economics but they can read or
read me they can follow English language
instructions they know how to run state
they know the run Matlab Sometimes they
know how to run all sorts of
a complicated Python or Giulia things.
Over the past year we've trained about 50
undergraduates to do this work with us
Mary with well just my graduate assistant
who is also on this call right now and
there's a few others who have helped me
in the past we trained undergraduates
do this and they do a very good job of
it so if we can train undergraduates to
verify the computation weepers ability it
should be relatively straightforward for
ph d. economists and tenured faculty and
longtime apply to Congress to do the same
thing goal is here to improve
the Expos reproducibility
goal is that when something is posted
with our articles on their website that
we can measure it with a very high
probability that it actually reproduces
after that there are still possibilities
that we missed something or
that it ran for us but the documentation
wasn't sufficient to replicate it 5 or
10 years from now we
don't know that we do or.
That and I mention that all this
information is publicly on the web there
are in the slides that at the end links to
these various websites where these are.
Replication template is also out there
it is a simple report that the students
write with lots of instructions
on what to do step by step.
And it's not the same thing as read me
because we're checking that everything has
but it very much aligns with.
What have we done these are statistics
from the end of November so
we are now April 1st of this that's
changed a lot but in the 1st 4 and
a half months as we were ramping up
we did 216 assessments 438 papers
Ok as of yesterday we have
approximately 600 assessments
and assessments are not the same
thing as manuscripts many
scripts tend to go through multiple cycles
we have yet to see a manuscript that it's
accepted on 1st pass but sometimes
turnaround can be quite quick and
this is an order of magnitude larger
than what most other journals are doing.
And that is an issue that we can talk
about in the discussion later on Ok.
We're still spending a lot of time doing
this it takes longer than we would like to
sometimes that's because
the computation is actually take long
sometimes it's simply because
we have received too many for
the kind of staff that we
have at present we have
18 undergraduates working on it we're
in the process of training another 15.
And.
There is enough rotation with these
students that these folks stay with me for
a while but also come summer
some of these will be going off
to work with various research
institutions for internships etc So
we are constantly training
new undergraduates to be or
are verified and
we work with various other agencies
2 of these have helped me in
the past the 3rd one has not yet so
that we outsource some of
the verifications as well Ok.
So what I mean with better archives so
once we've checked this the code and
the data should be in an archive Well
that's where our data and code repository
comes where in the past this was simply is
a file sitting on the web page now we have
Rich method they do that can be
added to the deposits we have a full
viewable listing of all the data of all
the files that are within this the posit
you can download them individually you
can download the entire deposit and
you get citations of these as well of
course it's necessary to link it back so
we have both linkages back to the article
and from the article to this using
the existing infrastructure of DUIs and
the linkages that are behind.
There is also arcane meditative stuff
within these pages whether that's Dublin
core or whether that's some Jaison stuff
that is also important for the fine
ability of these because now you can
actually find that through Google Scholar
or Google dataset search or some other
search engine that might be in use now or
in the future so
this integrates the deposits into a very
powerful way of accessing both the data
in through the data back to the article
some statistics from what we've
done about 72 percent of all
data that all articles that
we use use Stay don't.
Need 2 percent use Matlab and
there's a sprinkling of open source so
the bulk of what we see comes
from state and that is that.
Is that comparable to other sciences
No it's not there are very different
software usages across the disciplines and
this is one testament of it but
it may say life easier because we can
focus on getting our undergrads trained
on these 2 items are there differences
in the reproducibility of that.
The analysis for that is to follow.
Ok And finally better provenance tracking
and this goes back to that in a situation
is and often very intense working
with the authors to improve so
there's a teaching principle say
that you actually want to put
the proper credits and attribute
into the provider of the data and
this is one of our sample citations
that has been on the A's website for
the past decade and yet most of the time
these are absent from from the manuscripts
but we want this to be clearly and
precisely document so we go
through the manuscript the article itself
the online appendix that read me and
verify is is the is
the particular data object said
is there additional information
on access do you as the u.r.l.
actually lead to exact data if you want
to download the c.p.s. from the u.s.
Census Bureau website you can't
just quote w w that sense that
is insufficient to actually get to
the data without additional research
if there is an application procedure
do we have enough information to find
the application procedure are the other
access procedures described
if they are they complicated
are they do they last long is
there money involved is there time
involved is there Ira be involved so
all these things are important for
research or
to assess how complicated might it be
to actually reproduce this particular.
And finally I mentioned this
earlier is a license for
data use information should the author
provide the data so we have had
quite a few cases where the author says
I can't provide you with the data and
we check the information about the usage
rights that the author acquired and
the answer might actually be yes and then
unless we find a reasonable repository for
the data the author actually has to
provide the converse Lee we often check
whether the author is allowed to
provide that and again we have checked
some data use agreements and have told
the authors know if you actually cannot
provide this data thank you for providing
it to us for application but you don't
have to remove it from the archive these
are important aspects as we go through
the overall provenance documentation and
author struggle with this.
We have saved authors from
infringing on their data use agreements by
2nd guessing their ability to provide us
with an author says I think I've
obviously getting the data enough.
We will ask the question whether or not
their data provider actually thinks that
she's created or anonymised or
otherwise post-process the data but they
don't publish a struggle with it as well
they make it very hard to find exactly or
else going to call up the o.e.c.d. here
because they know that the o.e.c.d. is
actually working on changing this website
to something that actually allows the user
to do that as you navigate the o.e.c.d.
statistics the euro doesn't change when it
does change it doesn't change again when
you sort of dig down into their table so
that is quite hard to actually cite
the precise table that you want
somebody to you have to literally
describe how you navigate this issue.
Can you download the data or not lots of
academic data publishers research groups
etc Put it out there and as it turns
out there's a copyright on it and
unless you ask for permission that
copyright says you cannot redistribute
the data unless you invoke some sort
of fair use and good luck with that but
these folks are also
open to discussions so
when we see something like that and
we see it for the 2nd time we go and
ask folks whether or not that is
actually their intent and for for
this particular site would you see is
actually an archive because after we asked
they changed their license very clearly to
Creative Commons which explicitly allows
you to redistribute the data and
other say they're not going to do that
that they want authors to go back to their
original website to download the data
many websites now provide
a suggested academic style citation.
The St Louis Fed does an excellent job
with that citing both the original
provider of the data as well
as where you got the data so
those 2 elements are that you are all
that they provide within that city is 100
percent sufficient to recover
the data at that point in time and
finally restricted access data
is also perfectly feasibly
documented in such a way that German
r.t.c. has done an excellent job of
assigning DUIs to each one of their
confidential restricted access dataset and
all versions there are of listing them on
a website and that DUI leads to a page for
each of these various versions
that describes among other things
the requirements for data access so
those are important aspects.
And the question here and open in
the floor with some suggestions 1st for
authors the key to creating
reproducible code and
data archives is to follow some robust
coding lines automate as much as possible.
If we have seen code archives
that had manual changes to.
2 various programs $37.00 times in
order to generate various aspects
of the robustness checks that is can
be automated we have seen authors write
Fortran programs and Rican pile every
time that they changed the premise or
somewhere on line 750 of the code
use methods to circle for
cycle through programs think of.
Only slightly more sophisticated
programming tools that each and
every one of these programming languages
has and at the end when you're done with
your manuscript before you submit
it run all that analysis code again
there are cabinets to suppose
your analysis runs for 3 months
that is probably not doable so
keep meticulous logs and
sure that all the aspects are done in a
way that you you can still figure out how
you ran the 1st part of this by the time
that you get to the last we recently had
a very long discussions with authors
who are using public use data but
were using a model that required half a
1000000 compute cycles on a supercomputer
cluster we were not going to rerun that
but we were discussing with them how much
of the intermediate data they could
provide us and other authors in order for
at least parts of the analysis
to be efficiently
reproduced as part of the archive we're
still looking for the magic bullet for
that we prefer master scripts and
authors should prefer master scripts I
already mentioned no manual manipulation
also no manual copying of
results if you're writing
out results into one area and you for
the next that reference it in place
right out tables and figures don't
hand copy from various log files
compute all numbers in a package if
you've got instructions about this is
the city you can computed like this that's
also something you can stick into code and
then have the code say this
is what goes on page 5.
Some of the more subtle things are that
you might have been working on this paper
for 5 years and
you have all the packages necessary but
the next person out won't what
are the versions of those packages so
no manual install of packages to create
scripts to create all the prerequisites to
install necessary packages we provide
templates for that for state for our.
For Python it's embedded within the way
that Python environments can be set up
every single language has some way
of doing and not unimportantly when
you use those packages checked if their
package author who's done an enormous
amount of work that you're benefiting from
actually requires some citation again we
check that occasionally and as it turns
out many of your favorites either packages
actually want to be cited for the original
paper that they were created in or
wherever they are so do that because
that's how those authors get credit
you're not paying them you're giving them
credit in clear instructions we don't
need replicators do not need a long prose
description of the process of getting
a linear checklist is really all that
that's needed if that is not already done
by the master script that doesn't always
work but so have a clear instructions
provide the data cetaceans
they cetaceans are not hard.
Provided availability statements in the
review or the appendix What does it take
to actually get the data beyond simply
knowing where the data comes from and
there are very many tricky data Satish How
do you site at the us at that you extract
it from the banks credit card information
they base out of a particular date.
These are sight of all just as much as
other things were said a bill in the past
and we have a website where many
of these examples are given and
examples and how you can then cite.
We are currently discussing among
econ generals about incorporating
they develop build the statements and
incorporating a lot of the requested
information into a standardized meet
that then could be used by authors
an example of that is on the website
for institutions the key thing is that
many of these things many of these
new features are just that they
are new to most researchers and
so training in these novel methods
within various centers institutions etc
are important for current researchers for
future researchers So
universities have a role of integrating
this into curricula but it might just as
well be that this is the summer intern who
can that you get people to go through.
Institutions need to provide better tools
to streamline the process do you ice for
research data.
The positive mechanisms that
are integrated into how faculty work on
campuses how we search as work within
their institutions facilitating citation
by putting the obvious 87 ways
into the publication materials and
the websites that provide access to
the data and just generally awareness.
Training for replicators is not hard there
are a lot of instances out there Katie and
I are working on.
A training module at at bits I am
regularly training my own replicators for
the particular job project here has been
around and has some good guidance there as
well this is mainly
focused on on students but
all these materials can be repurposed for
staff training as well and
there may be scope to have formal
internal verification services
ask yourself as an institution what is the
reputational cost of Iraq Crucible outputs
What's the time and
money cost of verifying repairs.
But done right I can tell
you it's actually not a lot
there's actually some benefit to doing
it and ultimately what is the cost and
benefit of transparency if you're
publishing data if you're advocating for
things if you're a policy group
etc These are the mechanisms
exist already at universities so
these are 2 university based.
Verification services that essentially
provided as a service to the faculty
prior to submission does everybody
do that does every paper that
goes out from these universities
use these methods of course not and
how to scale this remains an open
issue when I mentioned earlier that.
We do this at the the a it doesn't come
for free and so one of the key concerns is
how can you scale this to other journals
to the general at mechanisms of doing so
preemptively checking code archives
conflicts with that restricted access
data so that tension between Access
reproducibility will remain and
in particular if one thinks of
tiered access in the federal system in the
United States that will become an issue
there are pilots undoing so
which was one of the certification
mechanisms that verification reckons that
we're using for public use it also works
with the French r.t.c. system and
offers of free service within the r.t.c.
to check code and reproducibility
within the secure confines and
with all the permissions and place and
finally your students your colleagues
are possible verifiers your
co-authors are possible verified and
the journals we have a job to do as well
any of the standards that I'm putting
forward your methods or tools they need
to be transportable across journals that
cannot be custom solutions so figuring
out what the common standard is and
believe me many of the things
that we see are not homogeneous.
So we've put together what my colleagues
it's called the Social Science guild.
Collects many of the sky ins
into one place it's expanding.
And we want to put this information
on the websites as well so
that this doesn't just get stuck
in some reach me on an archive but
also possibly become obvious right
on the landing page of a journal
by highlighting the aspects that relate
to how this data could be accessed.
These slides are at this particular DUI
You can also find it on the labor dynamics
get up and that's where you'll find
these additional resources as well and.